<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on David Winterbottom</title>
    <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on David Winterbottom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 17:05:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://codeinthehole.com/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beware of changing the &#39;related name&#39; of a Django model field</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/oe-related-name-outage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 17:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/news/oe-related-name-outage/</guid>
      <description>I wrote up a lesson on the dangers of renaming the related_name of a Django model field over on the Octopus Energy tech blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a custom Sentry client</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/oe-tech-custom-sentry-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 16:33:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/news/oe-tech-custom-sentry-client/</guid>
      <description>I wrote up a short tip on using a custom Sentry client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast.__init__ on Oscar</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/podcast-init/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 23:00:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/news/podcast-init/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed, along with Michael van Tellingen, on the &amp;ldquo;Podcast.__init__&amp;rdquo; Python podcast to talk about Oscar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 10:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/news/hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated this site to Hugo so I can host it on Github pages1.
Hugo is a fast and well thought-out static site generator, written in Golang. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to learn and has some neat features2 - the trickiest part is understanding the difference between various ways pages are organised: &amp;ldquo;sections&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;types&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;taxonomies&amp;rdquo; etc.
The Vim plugin vim-markdown provides good support for authoring Hugo posts since it supports syntax-highlighting for:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django, ELB health checks and continuous delivery</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/oe-tech-elb-health-checks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/news/oe-tech-elb-health-checks/</guid>
      <description>I wrote an article on Django, ELB health checks and continuous delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing for missing migrations in Django</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/oe-tech-missing-migrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/news/oe-tech-missing-migrations/</guid>
      <description>Octopus Energy has a tech blog. I wrote an article on Testing for missing migrations in Django.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Octopus Energy</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/octopus-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/news/octopus-energy/</guid>
      <description>Last Wednesday was my last day at Yoyo Wallet. Thursday marked my first day at Octopus Energy.
I&amp;rsquo;m deeply excited about Octopus. Through innovative use of technology, especially automation and cloud computing, Octopus Energy is going to radically change how people consume and pay for energy in the UK. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be both cheaper and massively better at customer service than the much-maligned incumbents.
Right now, we&amp;rsquo;re looking to build a superb tech team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>commandlinefu.com is in new hands</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/commandlinefucom-is-in-new-hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/news/commandlinefucom-is-in-new-hands/</guid>
      <description>For the record, I no longer maintain commandlinefu.com. I&amp;rsquo;ve handed over the baton to notable Bay Area celebrity, Jon Hendren (@fart). This is a good thing for the site and its users as I have been unable to do much maintenance in recent times. I look forward to seeing how the site evolves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewriting codeinthehole.com</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/rewriting-codeintheholecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/news/rewriting-codeintheholecom/</guid>
      <description>I rewrote this blog recently with the following aims:
 to make it as easy as possible to create a new article, using reStructuredText (RST); to clean up and simplify the design, focussing on the readability of articles that include code snippets.  I knew that there were various static blogs out there, with many supporting RST, but I still fancied the challenge of crafting something specific to my needs. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with wheel re-invention if you want to learn about wheels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
