<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>django-oscar on David Winterbottom</title>
    <link>https://codeinthehole.com/tags/django-oscar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in django-oscar on David Winterbottom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 23:00:20 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://codeinthehole.com/tags/django-oscar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast.__init__ on Oscar</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/news/podcast-init/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 23:00:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/news/podcast-init/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed, along with Michael van Tellingen, on the &amp;ldquo;Podcast.__init__&amp;rdquo; Python podcast to talk about Oscar.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The road to Oscar 1.0</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/projects/the-road-to-oscar-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/projects/the-road-to-oscar-10/</guid>
      <description>Oscar 0.7 was released this week, a comparatively minor house-keeping release that allowed us to reduce our pull-request and issue backlogs. We have a plan for Oscar through 2014 and this article outlines the roadmap.
v1.0 We&amp;rsquo;re aiming to be v1.0 before the end of the year1. Oscar has been beta for nearly two years and its APIs are stabilising. We&amp;rsquo;re ready to commit to the backward compatibility responsibilities associated with coming out of beta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command-line tips for effective release announcements</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/tips/command-line-tips-for-effective-release-announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/tips/command-line-tips-for-effective-release-announcements/</guid>
      <description>We finally released Oscar 0.6 last week. The process brought home the importance of writing your release notes as you go rather than at the end. It&amp;rsquo;s a real pain to extract the key changes from 1200 commits spread over the last 8 months. Lesson learnt.
This article is largely a note-to-self in case I have to repeat the process. However, if you do find yourself in a similar position, here are a few command-line tricks for analysing your git history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confoo 2012 presentations</title>
      <link>https://codeinthehole.com/talks/confoo-2012-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codeinthehole.com/talks/confoo-2012-presentations/</guid>
      <description>I gave two presentations at Confoo 2012 - below are the abstracts and slides.
Migrating from PHP to Python and Django Abstract:
 Many programmers cut their teeth with PHP before getting interested in Python. However, while the languages seem similar at first, there are many new concepts to grasp and a rich ecosystem of tools to master. This isn&amp;rsquo;t easy, but with the right advice, a strong PHP developer can become an excellent Python developer very quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>