<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on David Winterbottom</title>
    <link>http://codeinthehole.com/talks/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on David Winterbottom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://codeinthehole.com/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Confoo 2012 presentations</title>
      <link>http://codeinthehole.com/talks/confoo-2012-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codeinthehole.com/talks/confoo-2012-presentations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://codeinthehole.com/images/confoo2012.gif&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave two presentations at Confoo 2012 - below are the abstracts and
slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;migrating-from-php-to-python-and-django&#34;&gt;Migrating from PHP to Python and Django&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many programmers cut their teeth with PHP before getting interested in
Python. However, while the languages seem similar at first, there are
many new concepts to grasp and a rich ecosystem of tools to master.
This isn&amp;rsquo;t easy, but with the right advice, a strong PHP developer can
become an excellent Python developer very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the experience of migrating a development team from PHP to
Python and Django, this talk will examine how to tackle this journey.
While the fundamental languages differences will be touched upon, this
talk will focus on more interesting topics such as common python
gotchas, tips for grokking Django, awesome tools and applications from
the community, and how to manage such a migration for a large team of
developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;slidedeck&#34;&gt;
    &lt;script src=&#34;http://speakerdeck.com/embed/4f5127b373c922001f001c60.js?size=preview&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing-a-django-e-commerce-framework&#34;&gt;Writing a Django e-commerce framework&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django is well-suited for e-commerce, and there are currently several
nascent django e-commerce frameworks in development. This talk is
about the development of django-oscar, a framework designed to
leverage Django&amp;rsquo;s core functionality to allow domain-driven e-commerce
applications to be built. This is a very powerful approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing django apps which are flexible enough to be adapted to a wide
variety of scenarios is a non-trivial problem which will be explored.
The talk will also cover a range of e-commerce best practices and how
they can be implemented in Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;slidedeck&#34;&gt;
    &lt;script src=&#34;http://speakerdeck.com/embed/4f512f128a37d6001f003114.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commandlinefu presentation at Confoo 2011</title>
      <link>http://codeinthehole.com/talks/commandlinefu-presentation-at-confoo-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codeinthehole.com/talks/commandlinefu-presentation-at-confoo-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The presentation I gave at &lt;a href=&#34;http://confoo.ca/en&#34;&gt;Confoo 2011&lt;/a&gt; is now
&lt;a href=&#34;http://presentations.codeinthehole.com/confoo2011/&#34;&gt;available online&lt;/a&gt;,
there is feedback on &lt;a href=&#34;http://joind.in/talk/view/2896&#34;&gt;joind.in&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://codeinthehole.com/images/clf-presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides are written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://meyerweb.com/eric/tools/s5/&#34;&gt;Eric Meyer&amp;rsquo;s
S5&lt;/a&gt;, which is a XHTML, CSS and
Javascript based slide show format. I enjoyed using this as it was easy
to port my styles across from the website CSS file, it also means the
presentation is viewable as a normal webpage (no flash required).
However, the downside is that it is not easy to submit the slides to
Slideshare which is the common thing to do. There are a few work-arounds
out there but nothing good enough that I could find.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>